<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freedom of Religion Archives | Satoru Uchida</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/freedom-of-religion/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/freedom-of-religion/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 04:02:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Talk with Professor and graduate students who have been researching on mind control</title>
		<link>/2023/01/17/jan-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jehovah's Witnesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritual Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=236</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jan 17 After graduating high school, I made an appointment with one professor who specialized in mind control by &#8220;cults&#8221; such as Aum or &#8220;Unification Church.&#8221; He is very kind to me and invited me to join one of his classes for graduate students. It was before the assassination of Shinzo Abe, so I was [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/17/jan-17/">Talk with Professor and graduate students who have been researching on mind control</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Satoru Uchida</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4>Jan 17</h4>



<p>After graduating high school, I made an appointment with one professor who specialized in mind control by &#8220;cults&#8221; such as Aum or &#8220;Unification Church.&#8221; He is very kind to me and invited me to join one of his classes for graduate students.</p>



<p>It was before the assassination of Shinzo Abe, so I was just one of the rare examples of those who have experienced spiritual abuse by parents, and luckily Japanese Child Consultation Center (CPS-like organization) decided to take me from my parents. I learned many things from him and his students. The examples are how to investigate the impact of spiritual abuse or the existence of a research center that focuses on conspiracy theories.</p>



<p>It was the final period in Japan, so he and his students seemed very busy, but they warmly accepted me. One of his students is working on investigating the longer effect of spiritual abuse by surveying former followers of &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; Jehovah&#8217;s Witnesses, Happy Sciences, and some other new religions in Japan. I briefly reviewed the draft of the questionnaire and gave some advice on the use of languages.</p>



<p>After that, the professor talked about the current situation. He worried about the decrease of public interest in the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and spiritual abuse since the Japanese government currently seems they want to stop discussing this problem more because they made a &#8220;rescue bill,&#8221; which he thinks is not enough. But he worked for the guideline for Spiritual and close sorts of Child Abuse by MHLW, and we both feel it is enough to help children and youths who are suffering.</p>



<p>However, since he is a Social Psychologist, he knows few psychologists can deal with this complex problem. Because of that, he now aims to seek a way to increase the number of psychologists who have basic knowledge about religion and spiritual abuse through their education while trying to increase the number of students who want to be a psychologist.</p>



<p>Finally, he said it is very precious that I, who have experienced spiritual abuse and its after-effects while interested in spiritual abuse and advocating individual rights, am studying outside of Japan because this studying opportunity will give me a new perspective that cannot be gained from Japan. I don&#8217;t know how or if I have contributed to this problem so far, but I can definitely work on that in the future.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/17/jan-17/">Talk with Professor and graduate students who have been researching on mind control</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Satoru Uchida</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Talk with lawer who have been supported me</title>
		<link>/2023/01/15/jan-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritual Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jan 15 We met at the nearest shopping center of us. She was one of my referees of me when I won a scholarship from a Japanese foundation, Grew-Bancroft, and she has worked for me since I joined my previous residence after I left my home. We have kept in touch during the fall semester, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/15/jan-15/">Talk with lawer who have been supported me</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Satoru Uchida</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4>Jan 15</h4>



<p>We met at the nearest shopping center of us. She was one of my referees of me when I won a scholarship from a Japanese foundation, Grew-Bancroft, and she has worked for me since I joined my previous residence after I left my home. We have kept in touch during the fall semester, so it is natural for us to meet in person.</p>



<p>At the table, we mainly talked about our shared interest: spiritual abuse from the parents. Because of the publication of the guideline for Spiritual and close sorts of Child Abuse by the government, we discussed my current academic interest and college life in general. Both of us appreciate the guideline since it will help those suffering spiritual abuse. Still, we are worried about the lack of experts who can deal with these irregular types of abuses.</p>



<p>Also, while I am worrying about the politicization of the argument about the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and spiritual abuse, she accepted its politicization because she believes it is the best and fastest way to rescue those who are suffering.</p>



<p>When it comes to political standpoints of us, I feel I am a little bit conservative left while she seems liberal of liberal. Because of that, she is wholeheartedly working to advocate for children&#8217;s rights. I also wish to expand children&#8217;s rights, but I don&#8217;t feel the current Japanese situation is healthy. Japanese ruling and opposition parties seem to depend on one-sided information and purge one religious corporation. Although the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; has deceived many people through spiritual sales and illegal preaching, it is one of the certified religious corporations in Japan. I think I should respect it while enforcing the law against its illegal behaviors.</p>



<p>Because of this kind of thought, I decided to read right-wing magazines and seek what Japanese right wings are thinking about this problem. When I told this plan for her, she was interested in that and said please teach me when you find something interesting.</p>



<p>It was only dinner, so that we couldn&#8217;t talk much. But I think I found some interesting different perspectives from her. In this short but prolific conversation, I decided to focus on the interest for this problem based on right/left wings.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/15/jan-15/">Talk with lawer who have been supported me</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Satoru Uchida</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Read right-side magazines and left-side newspapers to grasp viewpoints of the right/left wing for &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2023/01/09/jan-6-jan-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jehovah's Witnesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soka Gakkai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritual Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritual Sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=58</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jan 6 &#8211; Jan 9 (last added Jan 27) &#8220;Seiron&#8221; 産経新聞出版局, サンケイ出版, and 産業経済新聞社. 1973. 正論 産経新聞出版局. https://ci.nii.ac.jp/ncid/AN00370131. After Oct 2022, they often discussed about this issue. On Jan 2023, they featured the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related issues. Hanada (added Jan 27) 杉原誠四郎. “「統一教会魔女狩り報道」を断罪する.” 月刊Hanada 2023 2月号 : 76–81. Akahata (newspaper published by the Japanese Communist [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/09/jan-6-jan-9/">Read right-side magazines and left-side newspapers to grasp viewpoints of the right/left wing for &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Satoru Uchida</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4>Jan 6 &#8211; Jan 9 (last added Jan 27)</h4>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-bjork-angled-separator-wide"/>



<h5>&#8220;Seiron&#8221;</h5>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>産経新聞出版局, サンケイ出版, and 産業経済新聞社. 1973. 正論 産経新聞出版局. https://ci.nii.ac.jp/ncid/AN00370131.</p>
</blockquote>



<ul>
<li>2022 Feb, no articles mentioning this topic</li>



<li>2022 Mar, some articles touched on the concept of &#8220;family,&#8221; which seems deeply affected by doctrines of the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; yet did not mention the term &#8220;Unification Church.&#8221;</li>



<li>no mention of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; until 2022 Oct
<ul>
<li>2022 Oct, mentioned &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; in some articles</li>



<li>One mentioned the relationships between religious corporations and LDP since LDP is currently making a coalition with New Komeito, which has Soka Gakkai (Buddhism New Religious Movement in Japan) as a power base</li>



<li>阿比留瑠比. 「空気」が支配する日本社会の異常. 産経新聞社, 2022.</li>



<li>One justified its relationships with the &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; arguing how the impact of the church was small for the ruling party, Liberal Democratic Party (LDP)</li>



<li>八木秀次. 「反アベ」の狂気ここに極まれり. 産経新聞社, 2022.</li>



<li>One criticized both right and left wings for this problem while partly praising the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related organizations&#8217; works, primarily related to N. Korea&#8217;s kidnapping of the Japanese.</li>



<li>三浦小太郎. 旧統一教会問題の本質は何か. 産経新聞社, 2022.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<p>After Oct 2022, they often discussed about this issue. On Jan 2023, they featured the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related issues.</p>



<h5>Hanada (added Jan 27)</h5>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>杉原誠四郎. “「統一教会魔女狩り報道」を断罪する.” 月刊Hanada 2023 2月号 : 76–81.</p>
</blockquote>



<ul>
<li>2023 Feb, &#8220;Condemning the &#8216;which hunt by media reports of the Unification Church'&#8221;
<ul>
<li>Criticize the attitude of media and politics</li>



<li>Insists the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; had not recognized guilty by the court for the assassination of Shinzo Abe</li>



<li>Criticize the government&#8217;s statement of &#8220;cutting off relations with Unification Church&#8221; before the order of dissolution (note: the order of dissolution haven&#8217;t released on Jan 27)</li>



<li>Supports the doctrine of &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; which advocates protecting &#8220;family&#8221; aside from their problematic spiritual sales</li>



<li>Argue how Japanese hates religion after terrorism by Aum</li>



<li>excerpts &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related media&#8217;s opinion as &#8220;fair and reasonable&#8221;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-bjork-angled-separator-wide"/>



<h5>Akahata (newspaper published by the Japanese Communist Party, JCP)</h5>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>赤旗編集局, 日本共産党中央委員会機関紙誌業務部, and 日本共産党中央委員会出版局. 2004. しんぶん赤旗. 縮刷版[CD-ROM] ed. 日本共産党中央委員会機関紙誌業務部; 日本共産党中央委員会出版局 (発売). https://ci.nii.ac.jp/ncid/AA11954267.</p>
</blockquote>



<ul>
<li>Skim from Oct 2022 to Dec 2022</li>



<li>Every once or twice a week, they mentioned &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and related columns, such as interviewing former followers of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; or Jehovah&#8217;s Witnesses, viewpoints from professionals.</li>



<li>They worked hard for this problem, but it may be because &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; has cooperated with LDP, and generally, Akahata newspaper tends to criticize LDP.</li>
</ul>



<h5>Oct 2022</h5>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><thead><tr><th>Day</th><th>Summary of Contents</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Oct 1st</td><td>reporting the number of cases of &#8220;scamming&#8221; by &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; (1165 cases, 2012-2022/09)</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 2nd</td><td>the pamphlet that criticizes JCP was posted by &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 3rd</td><td>advertising their publication focuses on the danger of the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 4th</td><td>accusing the cabinet members and opposition party&#8217;s diet member&#8217;s connection with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 5th</td><td>criticizing cabinet members and the Chairperson of the Policy Research Council for their deep connection with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 6th</td><td>reporting how the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; approaches those who are interested in marriage</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 7th</td><td>accusing LDP of its relationships with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 9th</td><td>how &#8220;Unification Chruch&#8221; built a relationship with Shinzo Abe</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 10th</td><td>accusing the governors of Toyama prefecture and Toyama city because of cooperation with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; during their election term</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 12th</td><td>reporting the lawyer&#8217;s group handed in the statement, which requests a dissolution order by the government</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 13th</td><td>criticizing the relationships between LDP and the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 17th</td><td>reporting how the followers of the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; worked or recruited the secretary of a politician (member of the house of representatives)</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 18th</td><td>the movement of requesting an order of dissolution for &#8220;Unification Church;&#8221; too much donation for &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 19th</td><td>accusing the LDP&#8217;s relationship with &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;; interview parents whose son once believed &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; but forced their son to leave</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 21st</td><td>reporting &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; confirmed its relationships with LDP members during the election</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 22nd</td><td>scoop the video from &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; that the president of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and LDP members, including cabinet members, are gathering in the same place and taking pictures smiling</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 23rd</td><td>focused on &#8220;Unification Church&#8217;s&#8221; project building a highway between Korea and Japan</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 25th</td><td>criticizing cabinet members who stepped down from their position because of not enough explanation for its relationships with &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;; accusing the LDP&#8217;s relationship with &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; including local authorities</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 26th</td><td>criticizing cabinet member who stepped down from its position because of not enough explanation for its relationships with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 27th</td><td>reporting LDP&#8217;s relationship with &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; during the last election for the house of representatives; focusing on awarding the person who worked for &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related school running at Mozambique</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 28th</td><td>accusing the LDP&#8217;s relationship with &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;; the press conference by the &#8220;second generation&#8221; of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and the interview for ex-Jehovah&#8217;s Witnesses</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 29th</td><td>the press conference by The Japan Society for Cult Prevention and Recovery requests making the guideline for spiritual abuse</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h5>Nov 2022</h5>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><thead><tr><th>Day</th><th>Summary of Contents</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Nov 1</td><td>Insider documents state, &#8220;donation is Japaneses&#8217; responsibility&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 2</td><td>Insider documents say, &#8220;sacrifice Japanese for Korea&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 3</td><td>accusing the LDP&#8217;s relationship with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; at the Kumamoto prefecture</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 6</td><td>focus on the &#8220;second generation,&#8221; how they were badly treated on &#8220;Syuren(similar to summer camp but more spiritual)&#8221; in Korea</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 7</td><td>accusing the LDP&#8217;s relationship with the &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; especially the LDP&#8217;s position of significant responsibility</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 8</td><td>focus on the hearing from ex &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and Jehovah&#8217;s Witnesses by the opposition parties in the house of representatives, the importance of making a clear guideline for spiritual abuse</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 9</td><td>the Prime Minister said the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; for victims of spiritual sales would deliberate on this session of Diet</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 12</td><td>the government sent 9.55M JPY for a &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related school in Senegal as ODA</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 18</td><td>illegal nature of &#8220;Unification Church&#8217;s&#8221; activities (preaching, donation, spiritual sales, etc.) based on past court cases</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 19</td><td>reporting the abstract of the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 22</td><td>&#8220;second generation&#8221; experiences violating of human rights based on religious activities through online investigation</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 23</td><td>Experience of one ex &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; member, including hiding sexual assault when they were committing religious activities</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 26</td><td>accusing the LDP&#8217;s relationship with &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;; experience of one ex &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; member, traumatic experience during college, including physical assault</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 28</td><td>Reporting the event that discussed the media&#8217;s attitude towards &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related problems</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><thead><tr><th>Day</th><th>Summary of Contents</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Dec 1</td><td>Require to recoup of an ODA for Senegal due to its relationships with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 3</td><td>Ask for reconsideration of the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; to make it more &#8220;effective&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 4</td><td>Reports the discussion table named &#8220;reveal Unification Church&#8217;s reality,&#8221; which JCP diet members joined</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 5</td><td>Focuses on adoption organized by the &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; which violates Japanese law that controls adoption agency</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 6</td><td>Ask for reconsideration of the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; to make it more &#8220;effective&#8221; &#8211; especially restrictions against donation</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 7</td><td>Ask for reconsideration of the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; to make it more &#8220;effective&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 8</td><td>Ask for reconsideration of the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; to make it more &#8220;effective&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 9</td><td>Ask for reconsideration of the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; to make it more &#8220;effective&#8221; despite the Diet enacted &#8220;rescue bill&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 10</td><td>Reports signature-collecting campaign which asks the government to dissolve the corporate status of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 11</td><td>Ask for reconsideration of &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; to make it more &#8220;effective&#8221; despite the Diet had enacted &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; and had ended</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 24</td><td>Examining why a considerable amount of &#8220;victims&#8221; of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; is female</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 27</td><td>Reports the petition by &#8220;second-generation&#8221; that asks governments to make &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; more &#8220;effective&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 28</td><td>Reports the Guidelines for Spiritual-related Child Abuses by MHLW</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 31</td><td>Reports the petition led by the former president of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; that asks the government to reconsider the order to dissolve the religious corporation</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-bjork-angled-separator-wide"/>



<h5>My reflection on this reading</h5>



<p>Left-side newspapers tend to criticize conservatives due to &#8220;connection with &#8216;Unification Church&#8217; related organizations,&#8221; however, left-side newspapers often interviewed or introduced &#8220;second-generations&#8221; perspectives. Personally, those &#8220;second generations&#8221; should also be aware of making connections with certain political sides; otherwise, they are doing the same thing as the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; did.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/09/jan-6-jan-9/">Read right-side magazines and left-side newspapers to grasp viewpoints of the right/left wing for &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Satoru Uchida</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The follower of Moonism sued local authority because of &#8220;violation of freedom of faith&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2023/01/05/january-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=56</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jan 5, Jan 12 On December 16, 2022, one man sued Toyama city because the resolution of terminating the relationship with the former &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; was passed by the Toyama city congress. The man claimed that Toyama city congressman and congresswoman refused his proposal to bring his petition against this resolution, which violates the right [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/05/january-5/">The follower of Moonism sued local authority because of &#8220;violation of freedom of faith&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Satoru Uchida</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4>Jan 5, Jan 12</h4>



<p>On December 16, 2022, one man sued Toyama city because the resolution of terminating the relationship with the former &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; was passed by the Toyama city congress.</p>



<p>The man claimed that Toyama city congressman and congresswoman refused his proposal to bring his petition against this resolution, which violates the right to petition, the fundamental part of democracy.</p>



<div style="height:2vw" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<p><a href="https://news.tv-asahi.co.jp/news_society/articles/000280071.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">news article delivering this news &#8211; Asahi</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>“旧統一教会信者が富山市を提訴 「関係断絶」決議で.” テレ朝news. TV Asahi Holdings Corporation , December 16, 2022. https://news.tv-asahi.co.jp/news_society/articles/000280071.html.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://www3.nhk.or.jp/news/html/20221216/k10013925361000.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">news article delivering this news &#8211; Japan Broadcasting Corporation</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>“旧統一教会信者が富山市を提訴 ‘関係断つ‘決議で精神的苦痛: NHK.” NHKニュース. Japan Broadcasting Corporation, December 16, 2022. https://www3.nhk.or.jp/news/html/20221216/k10013925361000.html.</p>
</blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p></p>



<h3>Translate and summarize the <a href="https://www.city.toyama.toyama.jp/gikaijimukyoku/gijichosaka/kaigiroku_iinkai_r3_2_2.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Toyama city congress report</a></h3>



<p><a href="https://www.city.toyama.toyama.jp/data/open/cnt/3/25765/1/040915giun.pdf?20230112133855" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sep 15</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>(page 1)The opinion briefs about &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; have been submitted by Toyama City Council&#8217;s LDP (Liberal Democratic Party), LDP, Civilian group of CDP (Constitutional Democratic Party) reflecting on the group of civilians who submitted petitions. New Komeito would convey thank you for those groups.<br>(page 2)However, the use of the opinion briefs, it seems New Komeito also agree with that, and considering the petitions&#8217; thought which want us to submit the opinion brief as a consensus of Toyama City congress, we would like to ask other parties to build unified version of the opinion brief.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://www.city.toyama.toyama.jp/data/open/cnt/3/25765/1/040921giun.pdf?20230112133855" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sep 21</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>(page 2)At first, I would like to ask your opinion about the opinion brief that &#8220;extinguish of former Unification Church and its related organizations and ask for help of victims.&#8221;<br>This opinion brief was handed in by Toyama City congress LDP, LDP, and Civilian group of CDP. Thus, I would like to ask New Komeito to express your attitude.<br>We agree with that.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>At the assembly held on September 28, they unanimously passed this opinion briefly.<br><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.city.toyama.toyama.dbsr.jp/index.php/7212994?Template=doc-select-frame&amp;VoiceType=select" target="_blank">assembly minutes, 44, 58, 59</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/05/january-5/">The follower of Moonism sued local authority because of &#8220;violation of freedom of faith&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Satoru Uchida</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Requesting Reports and Asking Questions&#8221; &#8211; Religious Corporations Act Article 78-2</title>
		<link>/2023/01/04/january-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritual Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritual Sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=53</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jan 5 What is the right of &#8220;Requesting Reports and Asking Questions&#8221; or &#8220;questioning right&#8221; This right can be exercised if the one who is in a religious organization continuously violates the law or the organization causes serious damage.After examining reports, the minister of MEXT can ask for the order of dissolution of the religious [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/04/january-4/">&#8220;Requesting Reports and Asking Questions&#8221; &#8211; Religious Corporations Act Article 78-2</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Satoru Uchida</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4>Jan 5</h4>



<ul>
<li>Since January 4, &#8220;Requesting Reports and Asking Questions&#8221; has been attempted twice by Agency for Cultural Affairs under the control of the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science, and Technology (MEXT).</li>



<li>The Minister of Education, Culture, Sports, Science, and Technology heard the opinions of an advisory council, Religious Corporations Council.</li>



<li> &#8220;Requesting Reports and Asking Questions&#8221; had been added to the article because of terrorism, mainly the Tokyo subway sarin attack, by Aum Shinrikyo but was never attempted until November 22, 2022.</li>
</ul>



<h5>What is the right of &#8220;Requesting Reports and Asking Questions&#8221; or &#8220;questioning right&#8221;</h5>



<p>This right can be exercised if the one who is in a religious organization continuously violates the law or the organization causes serious damage.<br>After examining reports, the minister of MEXT can ask for the order of dissolution of the religious organization for the court. When the court finds a cause, it may order the dissolution of the religious corporation.</p>



<p>The contents of reports and questions will not publish for a certain period because of &#8220;privacy for both sides.&#8221;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<h5>First Attempt</h5>



<p>The first attempt had excused on November 22, 2022. Based on MEXT, they asked for &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; to answer about the documents related to the operation of the organization, statements, documents, and accounting books related to their assets.</p>



<p>The agency received the answer for Cultural Affairs on December 9, 2022. However, the Agency said the reports from &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; were not enough, so they re-attempted the right on December 14, 2022, again.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<h5>Second Attempt</h5>



<p>Since the first attempt could not gain enough information from the &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; the Agency for Cultural Affairs re-attempted to exercise &#8220;questioning right&#8221; for the church.</p>



<div style="height:2vw" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>



<h6>References</h6>



<p><a href="https://www.japaneselawtranslation.go.jp/ja/laws/view/3898#je_ch8">Religious Corporation Act</a><br><a href="https://www3.nhk.or.jp/news/html/20221122/k10013899551000.html">news article by Japan Broadcasting Corporation, public media</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>“旧統一教会に「質問権」 行使は初めて 解散命令に該当か調査へ: NHK.” NHKニュース. Japan Broadcasting Corporation, November 22, 2022. https://www3.nhk.or.jp/news/html/20221122/k10013899551000.html.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2023/01/04/january-4/">&#8220;Requesting Reports and Asking Questions&#8221; &#8211; Religious Corporations Act Article 78-2</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Satoru Uchida</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Read News Articles and Press Conferences by &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; Day 2</title>
		<link>/2022/12/25/december-25/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Press Conference]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritual Sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=37</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Dec 25 As I did yesterday, I would like to continue to catch up on the current situation of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related issues in Japan. For today, I am going to focus on the press conferences and the announcements by the Church. It is a rare opportunity for us to grasp what they perceive and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/12/25/december-25/">Read News Articles and Press Conferences by &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; Day 2</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Satoru Uchida</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4>Dec 25</h4>



<p>As I did yesterday, I would like to continue to catch up on the current situation of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related issues in Japan. For today, I am going to focus on the press conferences and the announcements by the Church. It is a rare opportunity for us to grasp what they perceive and think about the problem, especially related to the &#8220;second generation.&#8221;</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<h5>First Press Conference</h5>



<ul>
<li>Held on July 11th, about an hour</li>



<li>Describe the official view of Mr. Abe&#8217;s assassination of the Church</li>
</ul>



<p>They excused themselves by explaining their doctrine and claimed their innocence for the assassination.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.businessinsider.jp/post-256503">First Press Conference (7/11): script</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>Yokoyama, Kotaro, and Rio Nishiyama, eds. “旧・統一教会が会見｢動機だとすれば重く受け止める｣田中会長が語る【会見全文】.” BUSINESS INSIDER JAPAN. BUSINESS INSIDER JAPAN, July 29, 2022. https://www.businessinsider.jp/post-256503.</p>
</blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<h5>Second Press Conference</h5>



<ul>
<li>Held on August 10th, about an hour</li>



<li>Their claim for spiritual sales and their political activities</li>
</ul>



<p>At the press conference, the president of the Japanese &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; Tomihiro Tanaka, made it clear that they are no more committing to spiritual sales, which was once a social problem in Japan about 40 years ago. He also resorted to the Church getting unreasonable discrimination and hatred rooted in &#8220;biased reporting&#8221; by the media. He said the current environment surrounding the Church violates freedom of religion.</p>



<p>When he talked about &#8220;biased coverage,&#8221; he pointed out that the media only convey the thoughts of &#8220;ex-Moonies&#8221; while omitting the viewpoints or &#8220;success stories&#8221; of pious Moonies.</p>



<p><a href="https://newsdig.tbs.co.jp/articles/-/120753?display=1">Second Press Conference (8/10): script</a></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>“【全文ノーカット】旧統一教会・田中富広会長会見「政治的介入や不正はない」: TBS News Dig (1ページ).” TBS NEWS DIG. TOKYO BROADCASTING SYSTEM TELEVISION, INC.　, August 10, 2022. https://newsdig.tbs.co.jp/articles/-/120753?display=1.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2022/12/25/december-25/">Read News Articles and Press Conferences by &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; Day 2</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Satoru Uchida</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
