<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Winter Term 2023 &#8211; Satoru Uchida</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/winter-term-2023/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 02:45:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>My thought about current news</title>
		<link>/2023/02/05/%e6%98%a8%e4%bb%8a%e3%81%ae%e5%a0%b1%e9%81%93%e3%81%ab%e5%af%be%e3%81%99%e3%82%8b%e8%80%83%e3%81%88%e3%80%81%e3%81%a8%e3%81%8b/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Generation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I wrote down my thoughts about current media coverage of this problem in both Japanese and English. 個人的に気になる点がいくつもあるので書き残しておきます。日本語は後半にあります。 If you are interested in original Japanese expression, please use DeepL Translator. The use of &#8220;second generation&#8221; in media I think the word &#8220;second generation&#8221; used in Japanese media includes too many groups. Based on my observation, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I wrote down my thoughts about current media coverage of this problem in both Japanese and English.</p>



<p>個人的に気になる点がいくつもあるので書き残しておきます。日本語は後半にあります。 If you are interested in original Japanese expression, please use <a href="https://www.deepl.com/en/translator">DeepL Translator</a>.</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="#sec-1-en">The use of &#8220;second generation&#8221; in media</a></li>



<li><a href="#sec-2-en">Some radical measure proposals under the name of protecting children</a></li>



<li><a href="#sec-3-en">The media coverage</a></li>
</ol>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="sec-1-en">The use of &#8220;second generation&#8221; in media</h6>



<p>I think the word &#8220;second generation&#8221; used in Japanese media includes too many groups. Based on my observation, the current use of &#8220;second generation&#8221; implies negative nuance. However, as long as I know, several &#8220;second generation&#8221; are living happily. I don&#8217;t try to justify child abuse, but I will not say being &#8220;second generation&#8221; is unfortunate unless they complain or feel dissatisfied. Imposing to &#8220;know&#8221; something &#8220;in general&#8221; sounds similar to teaching only one religious belief as &#8220;Truth.&#8221; I haven&#8217;t come up with alternatives for the words &#8220;second generation,&#8221; but it needs more attention to nurture understanding of this problem in Japanese society.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="sec-2-en">Some radical measure proposals under the name of protecting children</h6>



<p>I think my freedom of thought and freedom of religion was violated as a &#8220;second generation&#8221; of Jehovah&#8217;s Witnesses. Thus, I appreciate the guideline from MHLW and hope it is enforced in Japan effectively. However, there are some movements from several groups (whether political or not) with more strict guidelines, including intervention in the family. As an individual who believes violated my freedom of thought previously, I strongly support freedom of thought. Because of that, I cannot accept the authority intervening in the family, which consists of the smallest unit in the democratic society. Maybe it sounds conservative, and I still struggle with wrapping up my thought in regard to this problem.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="sec-3-en">The media coverage</h6>



<p>At least for Jehovah&#8217;s Witnesses, an eschatological group, the ongoing situation might look like proof of the near-end days in their dogma. Although I have spent about four years without faith, I am sometimes scared because of what&#8217;s happening. For active Jehovah&#8217;s Witnesses, I cannot imagine how they are feeling now.<br>And current media seems to be consuming the problem for their profit. I worried this problem would be forgotten as other important topics in Japan.</p>



<p></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<p></p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="#sec-1">「宗教二世」問題という呼称</a></li>



<li><a href="#sec-2">信教の自由、思想の自由を無視した対策の提言</a></li>



<li><a href="#sec-3">宗教弾圧とも取れる報道のあり方</a></li>
</ol>



<p>それぞれについて。</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="sec-1">「宗教二世」問題という呼称</h6>



<p>宗教二世という呼称は、あまりに多くの集団を含みすぎているのではないか。僕が知っている限りで、エホバの証人に残り幸せを享受している二世・三世の方々はそれなりにいる。もちろんそこに虐待がないかと言われればそうは言い切れない。しかし本人が幸せであるなら、本人を「保護」するのではなく虐待的な育児から離れるよう親を動かす指導・説得なのではないか？野球部でパワハラや暴力があったから野球部を辞めさせましょう、本人は辞めたくないと言っているけど関係ありませんという親がいたら僕は流石に強引だと止める。そこでなければ幸せになれないかもしれない。少なくとも僕は、成長して広い世界を知るにつれて不幸になっていったと思っている。知らないでいることが幸せかもしれない。「知ること」を押し付けるのは、今叩かれている宗教の押し付けと大して変わらないのではないか。（「知ること」は一般常識や日本の社会体制、現代科学への信頼などをざっくり表現したくて使ってます）この上で、宗教二世/二世信者＝被害者のようにラベリングしている現在の報道にはあまり良い感情を抱いていない。だからと言って代わりになんと呼べばいいかと言われれば分からない。ただ、僕は違和感を覚えている。</p>



<p></p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="sec-2">信教の自由、思想の自由を無視した対策の提言</h6>



<p>この点はどれだけ考えても答えが出ないので触れないでおこうとも思ったが、現在の自分の考えを書き留めておく。僕はエホバの証人の二世として育ち、信教の自由を侵害されたと考えている。だが、宗教を子どもから取り上げようとか「宗教の信仰等に関係する児童虐待等」のガイドラインで規定されている行為を超えて宗教活動に子どもが関わっていたら児相に通告しようと言った考えには反対する。僕はこの社会も一種の宗教のようなものに従って動いていると理解している。法律を破ると罰がある、科学はだいたい正しい(←コロナ絡みでだいぶ怪しくなったけど)、みたいな。それを信仰している人が多数派だから今の社会は回ってて、少数派の宗教が問題になるのも多数派から外れすぎているから。虐待だって、それを規定する考えや言葉が多数派に受け入れられなければ存在しないはずだ。ついでに、信教の自由を侵害されたと思い込んでいる人間として、信教の自由と思想の自由は守られなければならないと強く信じている。国家権力がこの領域、とくに家族に踏み込むことは絶対にだめだと信じている。さらに僕の考えだが、日本という国がそこに踏み込んだらいいことが起きないと思っている。もう少し日本を信頼していたら、フランスのホームスクール禁止レベルの介入はしてもいいと言っていただろう。まぁ、個人の考えです。</p>



<p></p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="sec-3">宗教弾圧とも取れる報道のあり方</h6>



<p>この点が一番の懸念だ。少なくともエホバの証人にとって。彼らの教義は終末論的だが、その流れをざっくり説明するとこう。今は終わりの日で、もうすぐ終わりが来る。終わりが来る前に、世界中を天災が襲い、エホバの証人以外の宗教がありとあらゆる国家権力によって弾圧され、「平和だ、安全だ」と宣言がある。その後エホバの証人が弾圧され始めたらキリストが臨在し地上を楽園にしていく。今の流れは、ちょうど宗教弾圧のところに見えるのだ。異常気象、戦争、宗教弾圧。ここまではっきり終わりの日のしるしが見えたら信仰を捨てたはずの僕でさえ怖くなる。それは置いておいても、日本社会における宗教のイメージが悪くなってしまうことを危惧している。僕は、宗教は必要だと強く信じている。信仰を求めて彷徨っていた頃、ある正教会の信仰者の方が僕におっしゃった「年老いて必要を感じたら来ればいい」という言葉の通りだ。共同体としての宗教は、今の日本にこそ必要なのかもしれないとさえ考えている。宗教は悪ではない。宗教だから距離を置く、霊的なものを遠ざける。そんなものは対策でも何もない、問題の先送りだろう。さらに、現在の報道はこの問題を消費しているように感じる。結局モリカケや今まで忘れ去られてきた問題のように、消えていくのではないか。</p>



<p>ざっくり書き殴っただけなので、細かい表現とか多少の読みにくさは見逃してください。今後も時間があるときに見直すつもりです。(最終更新: 2023/2/5)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reflection of Winter Term 2023</title>
		<link>/2023/01/29/jan-29/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=289</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This winter term project was exciting and stressful at the same time. The topic I chose is very controversial, and I found myself in a conflict between different myselfs. Part of me believes the law should protect children, but another part of me believes government should not interrupt religious activities. Reading news reports and governmental [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This winter term project was exciting and stressful at the same time. The topic I chose is very controversial, and I found myself in a conflict between different myselfs. Part of me believes the law should protect children, but another part of me believes government should not interrupt religious activities. Reading news reports and governmental statements also deeply shook my mind because those documents include really realistic descriptions of spiritual abuse or physical, sexual, and psychological abuse and neglect. That also made me depressed, but I think this kind of issue accompanies this. I realized how hard it would be if I chose to study in this field, which is one thing I gained from the project.</p>



<p>Despite the depressive nature of the research, I found it interesting because it directly relates to human rights. Human rights are somewhat vague to me, but I am living because of that rights. Then, how far can individuals exceed the rights against other individuals&#8217; rights or laws? This question also shaped the thesis of my undergraduate education so far: how to balance fundamental rights in society. I especially want to explore eastern societies, such as Japan, South Korea, and Taiwan, when I mention &#8220;the society.&#8221; Those countries encourage individual rights, which sounds very western, while consciously or unconsciously maintaining eastern or ancient Chinese ethics. I wish to study fundamental rights and how society works with broader perspectives, including religion, psychology, math, and more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Utilize Google Trends to examine public interests toward the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2023/01/27/jan-27/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Trends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=272</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Abstract Background The public interest in the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; has been one of the most influential factors in supporting those who experienced spiritual abuse in Japan since almost no attention had been paid before the assassination of Shinzo Abe. TV shows, newspapers, and tabloids eagerly report the news because of the high public interest in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Abstract</h3>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Background</h4>



<p>The public interest in the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; has been one of the most influential factors in supporting those who experienced spiritual abuse in Japan since almost no attention had been paid before the assassination of Shinzo Abe. TV shows, newspapers, and tabloids eagerly report the news because of the high public interest in the organization. It means a decrease in the public interest against the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; directly affects supporting those who have been spiritually abused. Analyzing the huge number of queries gathered by Google services reveals the public interest in the &#8220;Unification Church.&#8221;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Objectives</h4>



<p>Using Google Trends, I studied the public interest in queries towards <em>unification</em>, <em>unification church</em>, <em>former unification church</em>, and <em>family federation</em>. Each word is originally Japanese. I hypothesize that these data may be correlated with the assassination of Shinzo Abe and upcoming reports about the &#8220;Unification Church.&#8221;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Methods</h4>



<p>Google Trends was employed to normalize search queries on Google Search, Youtube Search, and Google News on a scale from 0 (includes 0% to &lt;1% of the peak volume) to 100 (peak of traffic) presented as weekly relative search volume (RSV) treating <em>unification</em>, <em>unification church</em>, <em>former unification church</em>, and <em>family federation</em> as search terms. A search time series covered the last 260 weeks (January 2018 to January 2023), and the RSV of all terms was compared with their weekly volumes. Respective trendlines were employed to estimate overall trends.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Results</h4>



<p>I found a dramatic trend immediately after the assassination of Shinzo Abe, but it shrunk quickly. Before the assassination, there was almost no interest in the &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; while Shinzo Abe and other ruling party members attended events held by the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and its related organizations.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusions</h4>



<p>Considering these findings, it may be reasonable to say the media have consumed the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related reports. After a certain period that those media conveyed sensational reports, public interest in the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; shrunk. This investigation utilized Youtube queries, Google search, and Google News; thus, it would include those who gain information mainly from Youtube and other video platforms.</p>



<p>Followed the abstraction structure of the paper below:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Vasconcellos-Silva, Paulo Roberto et al. “Using Google Trends Data to Study Public Interest in Breast Cancer Screening in Brazil: Why Not a Pink February?.” JMIR public health and surveillance vol. 3,2 e17. 6 Apr. 2017, doi:10.2196/publichealth.7015</p>
</blockquote>



<p>&lt;Figure 1&gt;</p>



<div class="iframe-wrap">
<iframe seamless="" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vT7Z1Xg3bt7YURoutWRvrGBGN0Jb4hTeKqXPCqkrLmg3dP9JN0BwlwxltN1EVt_OXvzi2-EmYqpiDgm/pubchart?oid=853583405&amp;format=interactive"></iframe>
</div>



<p>&lt;Figure 2&gt;</p>



<div class="iframe-wrap">
<iframe seamless="" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vRNwYgt0DuU0_TXeAjTCWFDPMWZgJAHl2a5yhPnB6Zkaiucjoe3DEj6LCB1grwKO6lPt-_jrrUagBA2/pubchart?oid=1091730905&amp;format=interactive"></iframe>
</div>



<p>&lt;Figure 3&gt;</p>



<div class="iframe-wrap">
<iframe seamless="" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vQBEtd1NjrxoveWZ8aGQp9bVwAu-eBbwLiUGIv2MtttInU_YPv3aJVGrK-EdalTXYTq_X5P_9_2Wr5u/pubchart?oid=1264133652&amp;format=interactive"></iframe>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Administrative Guidance for the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; about children&#8217;s adoption</title>
		<link>/2023/01/24/jan-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jan 24 Summary Jan 23, MHLW announced they did administrative guidance against the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; because of their work as an adoption agency, which they did not register. Japanese law dictates adoption agencies register for children&#8217;s adoption. So the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; did illegal work, and this had been questioning by attempting &#8220;Requesting Reports and Asking [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Jan 24</h4>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Summary</h4>



<p>Jan 23, MHLW announced they did administrative guidance against the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; because of their work as an adoption agency, which they did not register. Japanese law dictates adoption agencies register for children&#8217;s adoption. So the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; did illegal work, and this had been questioning by attempting &#8220;Requesting Reports and Asking Questions&#8221; or &#8220;questioning right.&#8221;</p>



<p>I used DeepL translator for this translation since I did not have enough time for this work.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-wide"/>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading">Compliance with relevant laws and regulations regarding adoptions, etc.</h6>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>On December 9, 2022, we issued a &#8220;Notice Concerning Compliance with the Law-related the Protection of Children in the Mediation of Adoptions by Private Adoption Agencies&#8221; (Office Communication, Family Welfare Division, Child and Family Bureau, Ministry of Health, Labor and Welfare, dated December 9, 2022) to your organization.</p>



<p>The Government of Japan is continuing to investigate the facts about adoptions that have taken place in the past among the followers of your organization. The Law Concerning Protection of Children in Adoption Proceedings by Private Mediation Agencies (Law No. 110 of 2016, hereinafter referred to as &#8220;Mediation Law&#8221;) The following notice is given with the understanding that the purpose of the Law-related Protection of Children and Promotion of Welfare of Children (hereinafter referred to as the &#8220;Adoption Mediation Law&#8221;) and the Law Concerning Protection of Children in Relation to Adoption Mediation by Private Mediation Agencies (hereinafter referred to as the &#8220;Mediation Law&#8221;) is to protect children and promote their welfare.</p>



<p>The following is the notice.</p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>1 Purpose of the Law</strong></p>



<p><em>(1) Positioning of the right to be fostered by the biological parents and adoption</em></p>



<p>Article 7 of the Convention on the Rights of the Child stipulates that a child &#8220;has the right to be known and to be cared for by his or her parents as far as possible.&#8221;</p>



<p>Article 1 of the Child Welfare Law stipulates that &#8220;every child has the right to be properly cared for in accordance with the spirit of the Convention on the Rights of the Child (abbreviated) and to have other welfare equally guaranteed&#8221;, and Article 3-2 stipulates that the national and local governments shall &#8220;ensure that children are raised in their homes in good health, both physically and mentally. In addition, Article 3-2 stipulates that &#8220;the national and local governments shall support the guardians of children so that children are brought up in their families in good mental and physical health. However, in cases where it is difficult or inappropriate to take care of a child at home, necessary measures shall be taken to ensure that the child is continuously taken care of in a child-rearing environment similar to that of the child&#8217;s home. In this case, it is stated that &#8220;the Child Welfare Law, etc., shall be applied to the child. In this case, the &#8220;promulgation of the Act for Partial Revision of the Child Welfare Act, etc.&#8221; (Hoyu Kodomo Houkokusho No. 0603/1, 2016) states that &#8220;home&#8221; refers to an environment where the child is cared for by his/her biological parents or relatives, and &#8220;a child-rearing environment similar to that in a home&#8221; refers to a home through adoption, etc.</p>



<p>Thus, the Convention on the Rights of the Child, which Japan has ratified, and the Child Welfare Law clearly stipulate that children have the right to be cared for by their biological parents as much as possible.</p>



<p>The Adoption Mediation Law also stipulates that &#8220;a license system shall be established for persons engaged in the adoption agency business, and measures shall be taken to ensure the proper operation of such business, thereby protecting children involved in the adoption agency business of private agencies, and at the same time, promoting proper adoption mediation by private agencies. The Act was enacted as a legislative act by the Diet members for the purpose of &#8220;contributing to the promotion of the welfare of children by taking measures to ensure that children are protected in the adoption proceedings by private agencies, and by promoting appropriate adoption proceedings by private agencies.</p>



<p>Article 3, paragraph 1 of the Law stipulates that &#8220;the adoption mediation shall be conducted with the best interests of the child in mind and in conformity with the best interests of the child&#8221; and the &#8220;Notice on the Enforcement of the Law Concerning Protection of Children in Adoption Mediation by Private Mediation Agencies (Notice)&#8221; (November 27, 2017 Child No. 1127, No. 4) was enacted as a legislative measure. In the &#8220;Notice on the Enforcement of the Act on the Protection of Children in Relation to the Mediation of Adoption by Private Mediation Agencies (Notice No. 1127-4 of November 27, 2017),&#8221; it is stated that &#8220;the significance of the adoption system in child welfare is to provide a warm home to a child who has no guardian or is disadvantaged and to provide legal stability to the child&#8217;s care, thereby ensuring the sound development of the child, and adoption shall be conducted solely from the perspective of the child&#8217;s welfare. Adoption must be conducted solely from the perspective of the welfare of the child.</p>



<p></p>



<p><em>(2) Interpretation of &#8220;Mediation&#8221; and &#8220;Business&#8221;</em></p>



<p>In the same Enforcement Notice, the term &#8220;mediation&#8221; for adoption means &#8220;&#8216;to mediate between a prospective adoptive parent and a child and to talk to the child as a third party in order to facilitate the conclusion of the adoption&#8217; and is not a requirement for the conclusion of the adoption. In addition, the term &#8216;third party&#8217; shall mean a person who is a parent of the child or the child&#8217;s father or mother (including a person who is to become the child&#8217;s father or mother as a result of the birth of the child) and a person who is a prospective adoptive parent of the child. Hereinafter referred to as &#8220;parents of the child&#8221;) or the child&#8217;s parents. Or a person other than the child&#8217;s father or mother who has the right of care for the child (including a person who is to become the person who has the right of care for the child due to the birth of the child). The communication between the child and a person other than the child&#8217;s parents (including a person who should have the right to custody of the child due to the birth of the child) regarding information on both parties shall fall under the category of adoption mediation.&#8221; The adoption agency is required to &#8220;provide information on the adoption of a child&#8221;. The &#8220;conclusion of adoption&#8221; here refers to the point in time when the family court grants permission for an ordinary adoption in accordance with Article 798 of the Civil Code (Law No. 89 of 1896) or when a special adoption in accordance with Article 817-2, Paragraph 1 of the same Code is concluded. The term &#8220;conclusion of adoption&#8221; does not refer to the point in time when the prospective adoptee and the birth parents of the child to be adopted reach an agreement on the adoption of the child. In addition, in the same notice, it is stated that &#8220;the adoption of a child by a person who has been adopted by both parties is considered to be mediation.</p>



<p>In addition, the same notice states that &#8220;under this Act, the term &#8216;adoption agency business&#8217; refers to the act of mediating adoptions as a business. The term &#8220;carrying on as a business&#8221; means to carry out the same kind of activities repeatedly and continuously for a certain purpose, and even if it is a one-time act, it has the nature of a business if carried out with the intention of repeating the same kind of activities. Examples of cases in which a business should be considered to be a business are those that advertise that they provide adoption services, those that have an office and show signs that they provide adoption services, and those that have an office and show signs that they provide adoption services.</p>



<p>The &#8220;Examples of cases in which a business should be considered to be an adoption agency are when it advertises that it is an adoption agency or when it has an office and posts a sign that it is an adoption agency. In addition, the law also states that a commercial adoption agency may not be engaged in the adoption of children for profit. In addition, it is stipulated in Article 7, Paragraph 1, Item 5 of the Adoption Mediation Law that a person who intends to engage in the adoption agency business for profit cannot be licensed as a private adoption agency, and the giving and receiving of money is not relevant in determining whether or not a person is engaged in the &#8220;adoption agency business.</p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>2 Comments from those who have been adopted through adoption among believers of your organization</strong></p>



<p>After the media report on November 15, 2022, that your organization may be engaged in the adoption agency business without obtaining permission from the prefectural governor, we received comments from several people who were adopted through adoptions between believers of your organization, including their own experiences, their current feelings based on their experiences, and their opinions. Many of them said, &#8220;The birth parents are the ones who are the ones who are the most important. Many of them said, &#8220;If my birth parents gave me up for adoption because they could not raise me, I could understand, but if they could raise me but abandoned me, I wish they had never given me up at all,&#8221; &#8220;I used my life and my life to fulfill their teachings,&#8221; &#8220;My birth parents could have raised me, but they gave me up for adoption, and that hurt me so much,&#8221; &#8220;What is wrong with me? I would not have been born if it were not for the teachings of the church, which encourages having many children and giving them up for adoption.</p>



<p>If it were not for the teachings of the church, which encourages the birth and adoption of many children, I would not have been born. These people&#8217;s voices showed that their biological parents (birth parents) were not able to raise them and that they had no compassion.</p>



<p>The fact that they were adopted while their other siblings were being raised by their birth parents was deeply damaging to the children&#8217;s hearts after they grew up.</p>



<p>In addition, some of them said, &#8220;I want this to stop from the child&#8217;s point of view. I don&#8217;t want the next victim to suffer from the same mental pain as I did. </p>



<p><strong>3. Thorough Enforcement of Compliance with Laws and Regulations, etc. at Your Organization</strong></p>



<p>In the &#8220;Handbook on the Righteous Life for Blessed Families&#8221; (revised edition, 4th printing, published on January 31, 2019), which is published by your corporation, it is stated that &#8220;the offering of a child for adoption to a childless family is a beautiful tradition of the Family Association for World Peace and Unification in the sense that we can realize God&#8217;s family ideal together, centering on God&#8217;s love. It is a beautiful tradition of the United Families for World Peace and Unification.&#8221; &#8220;Families who have received the blessings of children from Heaven have the responsibility to share these blessings with families without children,&#8221; etc.</p>



<p>On the other hand, as mentioned above, the Convention on the Rights of the Child and the Child Welfare Law state that children have the right to be cared for by their parents as much as possible, and that adoption should be considered when it is difficult or inappropriate for the biological parents to care for the child.</p>



<p>The handbook also states, &#8220;Once an agreement is reached between both families, it must be reported to the Family Education Bureau. The handbook also states, &#8220;Once both families have reached an agreement, it must be reported to the Family Education Department; it should not be done by both families, or by the parish or church alone, or after the adoption ceremony. Once both families have reached an agreement, submit the &#8220;Application for Adoption&#8221; and family photo to the Family Education Department at Headquarters for approval by the president. After approval, the Family Education Department at Headquarters will contact both families and the head of the family department and their church will be notified by the Family Education Bureau. In addition, &#8220;Basically, all expenses related to the birth (regular medical checkups, etc.) are to be paid by the adoptee. However, until approval is received from the Family Education Department, no money will be given or received.&#8221; &#8220;It is necessary to have the head of the church and the head of the family department attend the birth and confirm that both families are in agreement on what to do in case of any health problems with the child,&#8221; etc.</p>



<p>On the other hand, as mentioned above, &#8220;mediation&#8221; of adoption under the Mediation Law means &#8220;to mediate between the prospective adoptive parents and the child and to take care of the child as a third party so that the adoption will be completed smoothly,&#8221; and it is considered to be &#8220;mediation&#8221; if it involves contacting both parties for information or taking care of the child even after both parties have reached an agreement to ensure the adoption will be completed smoothly. In addition, such &#8220;mediation&#8221; is considered to be a form of &#8220;mediation. Furthermore, if the agency advertises that it provides such &#8220;mediation&#8221; (i.e., facilitates adoptions), it is considered to be a business.</p>



<p>The handbook begins by stating, &#8220;It is the basis of our liturgy, so let us do our utmost to put it into practice. It is believed that believers refer to this handbook as the basis of their life of faith. On the other hand, the above statement in the handbook does not assume that children have the right to be cared for by their parents as much as possible, and there is a concern that believers may understand that adoption is arranged within your corporation.</p>



<p>In light of the aforementioned understanding of the parties involved in adoptions, as well as the purpose and content of the Convention on the Rights of the Child, the Child Welfare Law, and the Mediation Law, we ask that you comply with all laws and regulations and ensure that no acts that would constitute adoption agency business are conducted within your organization, and that you reiterate in your publications and other materials the purpose and content of the laws and regulations. We also request that you ensure that your publications and other materials appropriately describe the purpose of the laws and regulations.</p>
</blockquote>



<p></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>Proper Operation of the Act on the Protection of Children through Adoption Mediation by Private Mediation Agencies (Notice)</strong></p>



<p>We would like to thank you for your continued understanding and cooperation in the promotion of child welfare administration.</p>



<p>The &#8220;Act on the Protection of Children through Adoption Mediation by Private Mediation Agencies&#8221; (Act No. 110 of 2016, hereinafter referred to as the &#8220;Act&#8221;), which came into effect on April 1, 2008, has been implemented as follows. The &#8220;Law Concerning Protection of Children in Adoption Arrangements by Private Mediation Agencies&#8221; (Law No. 110 of 2016, hereinafter referred to as the &#8220;Law&#8221;) In light of media reports that the Family Federation for World Peace and Unification (FFPU) is suspected to be engaged in the adoption agency business without obtaining a license under the Law, we hereby issue the &#8220;Notice on the Proper Operation of the Law Concerning Protection of Children in Adoption Proceedings by Private Adoption Agencies and the Consultation System, etc. for Adoption Proceedings&#8221; (Notice) (hereinafter referred to as the &#8220;Notice&#8221;). (Notice)&#8221; (Child Welfare Bulletin No. 12009 No. 2, December 9, 2022), we have requested that your local governments ensure the proper operation of the Law and consultation systems for adoptions.</p>



<p>In order to ensure the proper application of the law, we have issued the attached notice to the Family Association for World Peace and Unification (FUAW) as of today.</p>



<p>We also ask that your local governments ensure that adoption counseling services are not conducted without the permission of the prefectural governor in your area of jurisdiction. In addition, we would like to request that, in the event that a party to an adoption with a religious background contacts the Child Guidance Center of a prefectural or other child guidance center, etc. for consultation regarding such adoption, such party should contact the Family Welfare Division of the Child and Family Affairs Bureau of the Ministry of Health, Labor and Welfare.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gather data from Google Trends for examining public interest in the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; after the assassination of Shinzo Abe</title>
		<link>/2023/01/20/jan-17-jan-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Trends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=228</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jan 15 &#8211; Jan 20 The API I used for gathering information Other parameters I would like to use Problems]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="has-text-align-left wp-block-heading">Jan 15 &#8211; Jan 20</h4>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">The API I used for gathering information</h5>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://pypi.org/project/pytrends/"><strong>pytrends</strong></a>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>unofficial API of Google Trends makes it easy to gather vast amounts of information from Google search
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Use keywords I chose when I tried to gather information from Twitter
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><code>統一 OR 統一教会 OR 文鮮明 OR 韓鶴子 OR 家庭連合 OR 祝福2世 OR 祝福二世 OR 祝福２世</code></li>



<li><code>２世 OR 二世 OR 2世 OR 宗教二世 OR 宗教2世 OR 宗教２世 OR 三世 OR 3世 OR ３世 OR 宗教三世 OR 宗教3世 OR 宗教３世</code></li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Codes used pytrends are the following:</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code>import pytrends
import matplotlib
import pandas as pd
from matplotlib import pylab as plt
font = {'family' : 'Noto Sans CJK JP'}
matplotlib.rc('font', **font)
import requests
from lxml import etree
from pytrends.request import TrendReq

# API Connection
pytrends = TrendReq(hl='ja=JP', tz=540)
# Set the search keyword
kw_list1 = &#91;'統一教会', '統一協会', '旧統一協会', '旧統一教会']
kw_list2 = &#91;'文鮮明', '韓鶴子', '家庭連合', '祝福二世']
kw_list3 = &#91;'統一', '祝福２世', '祝福2世']

pytrends.build_payload(kw_list1, timeframe='2022-07-07 2023-01-17', geo='JP')
df1 = pytrends.interest_over_time()

pytrends.build_payload(kw_list2, timeframe='2022-07-07 2023-01-17', geo='JP')
df2 = pytrends.interest_over_time()

pytrends.build_payload(kw_list3, timeframe='2022-07-07 2023-01-17', geo='JP')
df3 = pytrends.interest_over_time()

df = pd.concat(&#91;df1, df2, df3], axis=1)
df.to_csv("gt-church-20220707-20230117.csv", encoding="shift_jis")</code></pre>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code>import pytrends
import matplotlib
import pandas as pd
from matplotlib import pylab as plt
font = {'family' : 'Noto Sans CJK JP'}
matplotlib.rc('font', **font)
import requests
from lxml import etree
from pytrends.request import TrendReq

# API Connection
pytrends = TrendReq(hl='ja=JP', tz=540)
# Set the search keyword

kw_list1 = &#91;'2世', '二世', '２世', '宗教2世']
kw_list2 = &#91;'宗教２世', '宗教二世', '3世', '３世']
kw_list3 = &#91;'宗教3世', '宗教３世', '宗教三世', '三世']

pytrends.build_payload(kw_list1, timeframe='2022-07-07 2023-01-17', geo='JP')
df1 = pytrends.interest_over_time()

pytrends.build_payload(kw_list2, timeframe='2022-07-07 2023-01-17', geo='JP')
df2 = pytrends.interest_over_time()

pytrends.build_payload(kw_list3, timeframe='2022-07-07 2023-01-17', geo='JP')
df3 = pytrends.interest_over_time()

df = pd.concat(&#91;df1, df2, df3], axis=1)
df.to_csv("gt-gen-20220707-20230117.csv", encoding="shift_jis")</code></pre>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">Other parameters I would like to use</h5>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><code>pytrends.related_queries()</code></li>



<li><code>pytrends.suggestions(keyword)</code></li>
</ul>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">Problems</h5>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Because pytrends send a large number of requests to the Google server, Google frequently restricts my computer&#8217;s IP address to protect its server. The error message looks like this:</li>
</ul>



<pre class="wp-block-code"><code>pytrends.exceptions.ResponseError: The request failed: Google returned a response with code 429.</code></pre>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Talk with Professor and graduate students who have been researching on mind control</title>
		<link>/2023/01/17/jan-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jehovah's Witnesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritual Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=236</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jan 17 After graduating high school, I made an appointment with one professor who specialized in mind control by &#8220;cults&#8221; such as Aum or &#8220;Unification Church.&#8221; He is very kind to me and invited me to join one of his classes for graduate students. It was before the assassination of Shinzo Abe, so I was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Jan 17</h4>



<p>After graduating high school, I made an appointment with one professor who specialized in mind control by &#8220;cults&#8221; such as Aum or &#8220;Unification Church.&#8221; He is very kind to me and invited me to join one of his classes for graduate students.</p>



<p>It was before the assassination of Shinzo Abe, so I was just one of the rare examples of those who have experienced spiritual abuse by parents, and luckily Japanese Child Consultation Center (CPS-like organization) decided to take me from my parents. I learned many things from him and his students. The examples are how to investigate the impact of spiritual abuse or the existence of a research center that focuses on conspiracy theories.</p>



<p>It was the final period in Japan, so he and his students seemed very busy, but they warmly accepted me. One of his students is working on investigating the longer effect of spiritual abuse by surveying former followers of &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; Jehovah&#8217;s Witnesses, Happy Sciences, and some other new religions in Japan. I briefly reviewed the draft of the questionnaire and gave some advice on the use of languages.</p>



<p>After that, the professor talked about the current situation. He worried about the decrease of public interest in the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and spiritual abuse since the Japanese government currently seems they want to stop discussing this problem more because they made a &#8220;rescue bill,&#8221; which he thinks is not enough. But he worked for the guideline for Spiritual and close sorts of Child Abuse by MHLW, and we both feel it is enough to help children and youths who are suffering.</p>



<p>However, since he is a Social Psychologist, he knows few psychologists can deal with this complex problem. Because of that, he now aims to seek a way to increase the number of psychologists who have basic knowledge about religion and spiritual abuse through their education while trying to increase the number of students who want to be a psychologist.</p>



<p>Finally, he said it is very precious that I, who have experienced spiritual abuse and its after-effects while interested in spiritual abuse and advocating individual rights, am studying outside of Japan because this studying opportunity will give me a new perspective that cannot be gained from Japan. I don&#8217;t know how or if I have contributed to this problem so far, but I can definitely work on that in the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Talk with lawer who have been supported me</title>
		<link>/2023/01/15/jan-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritual Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jan 15 We met at the nearest shopping center of us. She was one of my referees of me when I won a scholarship from a Japanese foundation, Grew-Bancroft, and she has worked for me since I joined my previous residence after I left my home. We have kept in touch during the fall semester, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Jan 15</h4>



<p>We met at the nearest shopping center of us. She was one of my referees of me when I won a scholarship from a Japanese foundation, Grew-Bancroft, and she has worked for me since I joined my previous residence after I left my home. We have kept in touch during the fall semester, so it is natural for us to meet in person.</p>



<p>At the table, we mainly talked about our shared interest: spiritual abuse from the parents. Because of the publication of the guideline for Spiritual and close sorts of Child Abuse by the government, we discussed my current academic interest and college life in general. Both of us appreciate the guideline since it will help those suffering spiritual abuse. Still, we are worried about the lack of experts who can deal with these irregular types of abuses.</p>



<p>Also, while I am worrying about the politicization of the argument about the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and spiritual abuse, she accepted its politicization because she believes it is the best and fastest way to rescue those who are suffering.</p>



<p>When it comes to political standpoints of us, I feel I am a little bit conservative left while she seems liberal of liberal. Because of that, she is wholeheartedly working to advocate for children&#8217;s rights. I also wish to expand children&#8217;s rights, but I don&#8217;t feel the current Japanese situation is healthy. Japanese ruling and opposition parties seem to depend on one-sided information and purge one religious corporation. Although the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; has deceived many people through spiritual sales and illegal preaching, it is one of the certified religious corporations in Japan. I think I should respect it while enforcing the law against its illegal behaviors.</p>



<p>Because of this kind of thought, I decided to read right-wing magazines and seek what Japanese right wings are thinking about this problem. When I told this plan for her, she was interested in that and said please teach me when you find something interesting.</p>



<p>It was only dinner, so that we couldn&#8217;t talk much. But I think I found some interesting different perspectives from her. In this short but prolific conversation, I decided to focus on the interest for this problem based on right/left wings.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Japan decides to indict the man who shot Shinzo Abe</title>
		<link>/2023/01/14/jan-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jan 14 On January 14, Japanese prosecutors at the Nara prosecutor&#8217;s office said they finished the psychiatric evaluation of Tetsuya Yamagami, who got indicted on murder and firearm charges. The news reports that Yamagami wants higher education after his service term. I assume he wants an education that he could not get when he was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Jan 14</h4>



<p>On January 14, Japanese prosecutors at the Nara prosecutor&#8217;s office said they finished the psychiatric evaluation of Tetsuya Yamagami, who got indicted on murder and firearm charges.</p>



<p>The news reports that Yamagami wants higher education after his service term. I assume he wants an education that he could not get when he was young.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Ogura, Junko, Emiko Jozuka, Aliza Kassim Khalidi, and Heather Chen. “Japan Indicts Man Suspected of Murdering Former Prime Minister Shinzo Abe.” CNN. Cable News Network, January 13, 2023. https://edition.cnn.com/2023/01/13/asia/japan-shinzo-abe-assassination-shooter-indictment-intl-hnk/index.html.</p>



<p><br>“銃撃事件の捜査状況や山上被告の供述は｜NHK 奈良県のニュース.” NHK NEWS WEB. Japan Broadcasting Corporation, January 13, 2023. https://www3.nhk.or.jp/lnews/nara/20230113/2050012601.html.</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Talking about &#8220;second generation&#8221; issues with my friend</title>
		<link>/2023/01/10/jan-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jan 10 Today I met with my friend, who is studying at International Christian University as a senior. She finally decided to major in Anthropology, but she was also interested in advocation for children. She has worked on Save the Children Japan and advocated for educating the treatment of children&#8217;s rights. We talked about many [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Jan 10</h4>



<p>Today I met with my friend, who is studying at International Christian University as a senior. She finally decided to major in Anthropology, but she was also interested in advocation for children. She has worked on Save the Children Japan and advocated for educating the treatment of children&#8217;s rights.</p>



<p>We talked about many things, especially those related to our future careers. Because she is a senior, she has been working on job applications while I have just finished my first semester as a college student. But one thing we have in common: the undescribable anxiety for our future. Thus we spent a lot of time on this topic.</p>



<p>Anyway, about spiritual abuse. She seemed to focus more on supporting while the child is in the family and after the child leaves their family. Since I have experienced living in a group home, she talked about the quality of a group home.</p>



<p>My group home is awesome &#8211; of course, I am biased. But I heard very bad rumors from other group homes and rarely saw news articles reporting abuse in the group home, which should be a safe place for children.</p>



<p>And she said, &#8220;I guess some welfare workers treat children badly because they think of themselves as &#8216;who are helping the misery child&#8217; to some extent.&#8221; I agree with that. However, I do not know how to prevent that kind of person from getting a position in the group home. In Japan, almost any kind of welfare institution is always recruiting workers despite not having enough money to run the group home easily.</p>



<p>My group home, though, have a lot of money and has some lawyers working for children. The founder of the corporation which runs my group home seems very good at finding and gathering the people they need. But not every corporation is like that. Some institutions are suffering from a lack of money. Others are doing everything they can to hire. We concluded we should consider these problems while discussing treating spiritually abused children.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Read right-side magazines and left-side newspapers to grasp viewpoints of the right/left wing for &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2023/01/09/jan-6-jan-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sato]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Winter Term 2023]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jehovah's Witnesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Second Generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soka Gakkai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritual Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritual Sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unification Church]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=58</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jan 6 &#8211; Jan 9 (last added Jan 27) &#8220;Seiron&#8221; 産経新聞出版局, サンケイ出版, and 産業経済新聞社. 1973. 正論 産経新聞出版局. https://ci.nii.ac.jp/ncid/AN00370131. After Oct 2022, they often discussed about this issue. On Jan 2023, they featured the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related issues. Hanada (added Jan 27) 杉原誠四郎. “「統一教会魔女狩り報道」を断罪する.” 月刊Hanada 2023 2月号 : 76–81. Akahata (newspaper published by the Japanese Communist [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Jan 6 &#8211; Jan 9 (last added Jan 27)</h4>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-bjork-angled-separator-wide"/>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">&#8220;Seiron&#8221;</h5>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>産経新聞出版局, サンケイ出版, and 産業経済新聞社. 1973. 正論 産経新聞出版局. https://ci.nii.ac.jp/ncid/AN00370131.</p>
</blockquote>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>2022 Feb, no articles mentioning this topic</li>



<li>2022 Mar, some articles touched on the concept of &#8220;family,&#8221; which seems deeply affected by doctrines of the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; yet did not mention the term &#8220;Unification Church.&#8221;</li>



<li>no mention of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; until 2022 Oct
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>2022 Oct, mentioned &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; in some articles</li>



<li>One mentioned the relationships between religious corporations and LDP since LDP is currently making a coalition with New Komeito, which has Soka Gakkai (Buddhism New Religious Movement in Japan) as a power base</li>



<li>阿比留瑠比. 「空気」が支配する日本社会の異常. 産経新聞社, 2022.</li>



<li>One justified its relationships with the &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; arguing how the impact of the church was small for the ruling party, Liberal Democratic Party (LDP)</li>



<li>八木秀次. 「反アベ」の狂気ここに極まれり. 産経新聞社, 2022.</li>



<li>One criticized both right and left wings for this problem while partly praising the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related organizations&#8217; works, primarily related to N. Korea&#8217;s kidnapping of the Japanese.</li>



<li>三浦小太郎. 旧統一教会問題の本質は何か. 産経新聞社, 2022.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<p>After Oct 2022, they often discussed about this issue. On Jan 2023, they featured the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related issues.</p>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">Hanada (added Jan 27)</h5>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>杉原誠四郎. “「統一教会魔女狩り報道」を断罪する.” 月刊Hanada 2023 2月号 : 76–81.</p>
</blockquote>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>2023 Feb, &#8220;Condemning the &#8216;which hunt by media reports of the Unification Church'&#8221;
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Criticize the attitude of media and politics</li>



<li>Insists the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; had not recognized guilty by the court for the assassination of Shinzo Abe</li>



<li>Criticize the government&#8217;s statement of &#8220;cutting off relations with Unification Church&#8221; before the order of dissolution (note: the order of dissolution haven&#8217;t released on Jan 27)</li>



<li>Supports the doctrine of &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; which advocates protecting &#8220;family&#8221; aside from their problematic spiritual sales</li>



<li>Argue how Japanese hates religion after terrorism by Aum</li>



<li>excerpts &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related media&#8217;s opinion as &#8220;fair and reasonable&#8221;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-bjork-angled-separator-wide"/>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">Akahata (newspaper published by the Japanese Communist Party, JCP)</h5>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>赤旗編集局, 日本共産党中央委員会機関紙誌業務部, and 日本共産党中央委員会出版局. 2004. しんぶん赤旗. 縮刷版[CD-ROM] ed. 日本共産党中央委員会機関紙誌業務部; 日本共産党中央委員会出版局 (発売). https://ci.nii.ac.jp/ncid/AA11954267.</p>
</blockquote>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Skim from Oct 2022 to Dec 2022</li>



<li>Every once or twice a week, they mentioned &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and related columns, such as interviewing former followers of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; or Jehovah&#8217;s Witnesses, viewpoints from professionals.</li>



<li>They worked hard for this problem, but it may be because &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; has cooperated with LDP, and generally, Akahata newspaper tends to criticize LDP.</li>
</ul>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">Oct 2022</h5>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><thead><tr><th>Day</th><th>Summary of Contents</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Oct 1st</td><td>reporting the number of cases of &#8220;scamming&#8221; by &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; (1165 cases, 2012-2022/09)</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 2nd</td><td>the pamphlet that criticizes JCP was posted by &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 3rd</td><td>advertising their publication focuses on the danger of the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 4th</td><td>accusing the cabinet members and opposition party&#8217;s diet member&#8217;s connection with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 5th</td><td>criticizing cabinet members and the Chairperson of the Policy Research Council for their deep connection with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 6th</td><td>reporting how the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; approaches those who are interested in marriage</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 7th</td><td>accusing LDP of its relationships with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 9th</td><td>how &#8220;Unification Chruch&#8221; built a relationship with Shinzo Abe</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 10th</td><td>accusing the governors of Toyama prefecture and Toyama city because of cooperation with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; during their election term</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 12th</td><td>reporting the lawyer&#8217;s group handed in the statement, which requests a dissolution order by the government</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 13th</td><td>criticizing the relationships between LDP and the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 17th</td><td>reporting how the followers of the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; worked or recruited the secretary of a politician (member of the house of representatives)</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 18th</td><td>the movement of requesting an order of dissolution for &#8220;Unification Church;&#8221; too much donation for &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 19th</td><td>accusing the LDP&#8217;s relationship with &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;; interview parents whose son once believed &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; but forced their son to leave</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 21st</td><td>reporting &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; confirmed its relationships with LDP members during the election</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 22nd</td><td>scoop the video from &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; that the president of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and LDP members, including cabinet members, are gathering in the same place and taking pictures smiling</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 23rd</td><td>focused on &#8220;Unification Church&#8217;s&#8221; project building a highway between Korea and Japan</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 25th</td><td>criticizing cabinet members who stepped down from their position because of not enough explanation for its relationships with &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;; accusing the LDP&#8217;s relationship with &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; including local authorities</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 26th</td><td>criticizing cabinet member who stepped down from its position because of not enough explanation for its relationships with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 27th</td><td>reporting LDP&#8217;s relationship with &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; during the last election for the house of representatives; focusing on awarding the person who worked for &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related school running at Mozambique</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 28th</td><td>accusing the LDP&#8217;s relationship with &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;; the press conference by the &#8220;second generation&#8221; of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and the interview for ex-Jehovah&#8217;s Witnesses</td></tr><tr><td>Oct 29th</td><td>the press conference by The Japan Society for Cult Prevention and Recovery requests making the guideline for spiritual abuse</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">Nov 2022</h5>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><thead><tr><th>Day</th><th>Summary of Contents</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Nov 1</td><td>Insider documents state, &#8220;donation is Japaneses&#8217; responsibility&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 2</td><td>Insider documents say, &#8220;sacrifice Japanese for Korea&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 3</td><td>accusing the LDP&#8217;s relationship with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; at the Kumamoto prefecture</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 6</td><td>focus on the &#8220;second generation,&#8221; how they were badly treated on &#8220;Syuren(similar to summer camp but more spiritual)&#8221; in Korea</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 7</td><td>accusing the LDP&#8217;s relationship with the &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; especially the LDP&#8217;s position of significant responsibility</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 8</td><td>focus on the hearing from ex &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; and Jehovah&#8217;s Witnesses by the opposition parties in the house of representatives, the importance of making a clear guideline for spiritual abuse</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 9</td><td>the Prime Minister said the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; for victims of spiritual sales would deliberate on this session of Diet</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 12</td><td>the government sent 9.55M JPY for a &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related school in Senegal as ODA</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 18</td><td>illegal nature of &#8220;Unification Church&#8217;s&#8221; activities (preaching, donation, spiritual sales, etc.) based on past court cases</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 19</td><td>reporting the abstract of the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 22</td><td>&#8220;second generation&#8221; experiences violating of human rights based on religious activities through online investigation</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 23</td><td>Experience of one ex &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; member, including hiding sexual assault when they were committing religious activities</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 26</td><td>accusing the LDP&#8217;s relationship with &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;; experience of one ex &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; member, traumatic experience during college, including physical assault</td></tr><tr><td>Nov 28</td><td>Reporting the event that discussed the media&#8217;s attitude towards &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; related problems</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><thead><tr><th>Day</th><th>Summary of Contents</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Dec 1</td><td>Require to recoup of an ODA for Senegal due to its relationships with the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 3</td><td>Ask for reconsideration of the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; to make it more &#8220;effective&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 4</td><td>Reports the discussion table named &#8220;reveal Unification Church&#8217;s reality,&#8221; which JCP diet members joined</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 5</td><td>Focuses on adoption organized by the &#8220;Unification Church,&#8221; which violates Japanese law that controls adoption agency</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 6</td><td>Ask for reconsideration of the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; to make it more &#8220;effective&#8221; &#8211; especially restrictions against donation</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 7</td><td>Ask for reconsideration of the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; to make it more &#8220;effective&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 8</td><td>Ask for reconsideration of the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; to make it more &#8220;effective&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 9</td><td>Ask for reconsideration of the &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; to make it more &#8220;effective&#8221; despite the Diet enacted &#8220;rescue bill&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 10</td><td>Reports signature-collecting campaign which asks the government to dissolve the corporate status of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 11</td><td>Ask for reconsideration of &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; to make it more &#8220;effective&#8221; despite the Diet had enacted &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; and had ended</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 24</td><td>Examining why a considerable amount of &#8220;victims&#8221; of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; is female</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 27</td><td>Reports the petition by &#8220;second-generation&#8221; that asks governments to make &#8220;rescue bill&#8221; more &#8220;effective&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 28</td><td>Reports the Guidelines for Spiritual-related Child Abuses by MHLW</td></tr><tr><td>Dec 31</td><td>Reports the petition led by the former president of &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; that asks the government to reconsider the order to dissolve the religious corporation</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity is-style-bjork-angled-separator-wide"/>



<h5 class="wp-block-heading">My reflection on this reading</h5>



<p>Left-side newspapers tend to criticize conservatives due to &#8220;connection with &#8216;Unification Church&#8217; related organizations,&#8221; however, left-side newspapers often interviewed or introduced &#8220;second-generations&#8221; perspectives. Personally, those &#8220;second generations&#8221; should also be aware of making connections with certain political sides; otherwise, they are doing the same thing as the &#8220;Unification Church&#8221; did.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
